Daksh Kumar Singh

Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN - 47906

📳 +1(765)767-3274 | 🗷 singh988@purdue.edu | 🖸 github.com/daksh-kumar-singh | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/daksh-kumar-singh

Research Statement

A Purdue University undergraduate student who's research aims to optimize nanofabrication and characterization techniques through the integration of machine learning with quantum optics, plasmonics, and optical metamaterials. Focus is on studying the effect of topological variations of metamaterials and discovering novel applications for optical and physical properties of solid-state materials. Aims to contribute to a variety of applications, including integrated photonic circuits, quantum sensing, and quantum computing by developing high-efficiency, reconfigurable, semiconductor-compatible devices.

Education

Purdue UniversityWest Lafayette, Indiana

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

Aug 2022 - Current

- John Martinson Honors College
- · Quantum Science Center
- Courses: Multivariate Calculus, Python for Data Science, Electric and Magnetic Interactions, Electrical Engineering Fundamentals I

Work Experience_

Summer Undergraduate Research Fellowship

West Lafayette, Indiana

May 2023 - Aug 2023

Purdue University

- Selected for SURF at Purdue University to work on 'Machine Learning Assisted Plasmonic Fabrication'
- Awarded fellowship to work at research lab in Birck Nanotechnology Center, Purdue University

Undergraduate Researcher

West Lafayette, Indiana

Purdue University

Jan 2023 - Apr 2023

- Worked in nanofabrication and characterization
- · Learnt machine learning models to analyze quantitative data

Publications

CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS

Physical Verification of Unclonable Spectral Tags in Microelectronics Packaging

Daksh Kumar Singh, Yuheng Chen, Blake Anthony Wilson, Alexandra Boltasseva, Alexander Kildishev, Vladimir Shalaev Spring 2023, West Lafayette, Indiana

Achievements

Apr 2023 First-Time Researcher Award, Engineering Undergraduate Research Office (EURO)	Purdue University
Dec 2022 Dean's List , College of Engineering	Purdue University
Dec 2022 Semester Honors , College of Engineering	Purdue University

Skills

Fabrication	E-Beam Lithography, Etching, Photoresist Spin Coating, Cleanroom Certification (ISO Class 3-4-5-6).
Characterization	Variable Angle Spectroscopic Ellipsometry, Dark Field Microscopy, Scanning Electron Microscopy.
Certifications	Laser Safety Certified, Cleanroom Certified (Class 1-10-100-1000).
Programming	MatLab, Python (PyTorch, NumPy), C/C++.

Soft Skills Communication, Documentation, Leadership, Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-Solving.

Languages_

English Professional proficiency **Hindi** Native proficiency